Alexander Wiegman

Remote, USA (and sometimes Japan) | hello@madicetea.me | (209)-353-5377 | https://github.com/madicetea

Summary

Alex is an experienced analyst with a passion for computing systems, architectures, networks, and their security. He currently is pursuing a challenge to discover and apply concepts of compliance, security controls, and systems architecture to become an overall better security engineering professional in the solutions / security architecture fields.

Work Experience

GRC Analyst / Assistant Security Engineer Kong Inc. (San Francisco, USA) 08/2021 – (current)

The open-source name for API gateway solutions for microservices, both on-prem and in cloud. | https://www.konghq.com

- Automate, test, and train compliance questionnaires & documentation using industry workflow software and procedures.
- Contribute to compliance & business efforts from research on recent industry regulations, governmental policies, and laws.
- Evaluate between and implement competing choices for technical controls to meet security and compliance posture goals.

Cyber Security Analyst

PerimeterX, Inc. (San Mateo, USA)

11/2019 - 08/2021

Worldwide leader in behavioural bot management protection for e-Commerce apps.

https://www.perimeterx.com

- Lead and mentor to customers and multiple internal departments, alike. Evolved an onboarding program for the WFH era.
- Specialties in technical integrations, data logging solutions, high-value item AIO software research, JavaScript supply-chain risk, and information processing and asset (cookie, scripts, etc.) identification questionnaires.
- Automated alerting patterns and data query through parameterisation and scripting in YAML, SQL, JS, and Python.
- Identified multiple specific key patterns in anomalous network & client-side data points from Petabyte-scale data, then synthesised these into backend detection models to prevent and terminate account takeover, fraud, and card theft.

Cyber Security Analyst (Intern)

Pipeline Security, K.K. (Tokyo, Japan)

02/2019 - 07/2019

Leading provider of DNS security intelligence feeds to the Asia-Pacific (APAC) region.

https://pipelinesecurity.net

- Researched internal risk vulnerability by configuring secure policies & installing updates for cloud-hosted virtual machines, and programming a BIND DNS server with Response-Policy Zones to examine SIEM data visualization by ELK.
- Transformed customer image by contributing four articles of how-to documentation and negotiating a redesign of knowledgebase and homepage with co-workers, while providing production support to three customer companies.
- Investigated a false-positive spam listing, due to an issue identified in a shared hosting provider's nameservers (NS).

Skills

Certifications / Licenses AWS Cloud Practitioner (-2024); Microsoft Azure SysAdmin [Associate] (-2022);

CompTIA Security+ / A+ (-2024), Mobility+ / CDIA+ (lifetime)

Operating Systems Windows, Mac OSX, Linux (Fedora, ChromeOS, Debian, CentOS, Android, Ubuntu)

Programming, Scripting UNIX bash, SQL, VCL, JavaScript, Python, HTML, TOML/YAML, JSON, Java, Ruby

Programs / Toolkits AWS/CloudFormation, Fastly, Google APIs, BigQuery, VMWare, Prometheus, ELK,

CircleCI, git, SSH, homebrew, Insomnia, DNS/BIND, DMARC, Android Studio, JIRA

Websites Created / https://madicetea.me [2018-]

Contributed https://peakstudentcouncil.org [-2019], https://peakstudentcouncil.org [-2017]

Accomplishments GitHub Hacktoberfest Winner (2018 - 2021), CircleCl Orbtoberfest Winner (2020),

ICMCP Black Hat Scholar (2017)

Education

The University of Tokyo [UTokyo]

(Tokyo, Japan)

09/2015 - 09/2019

Bachelor's Degree in Environmental Science Minors in Informatics

Minors in Informatics & Science and Technology Studies